<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Know About Climate</string>
    <string name="todo">TODO</string>
    <string name="information_Q_1">
Ans. One of the first things you probably do every morning is look out the window to see what the weather is like. Looking outside and listening to the day’s forecast helps you decide what clothes you will wear and maybe even what you will do throughout the day. If you don’t have school and the weather looks sunny, you might visit the zoo or go on a picnic. A rainy day might make you think about visiting a museum or staying home to read.

\n\nThe weather affects us in many ways. Day-to-day changes in weather can influence how we feel and the way we look at the world. Severe weather, such as tornadoes, hurricanes, and blizzards, can disrupt many people’s lives because of the destruction they cause.

\n\nThe term “weather” refers to the temporary conditions of the atmosphere, the layer of air that surrounds the Earth. We usually think of weather in terms of the state of the atmosphere in our own part of the world. But weather works like dropping a pebble in water—the ripples eventually affect water far away from where the pebble was dropped. The same happens with weather around the globe. Weather in your region will eventually affect the weather hundreds or thousands of kilometers away. For example, a snowstorm around Winnipeg, Manitoba, Canada, might eventually reach Chicago, Illinois, as it moves southeast through the U.S.

\n\nWeather doesn’t just stay in one place. It moves, and changes from hour to hour or day to day. Over many years, certain conditions become familiar weather in an area. The average weather in a specific region, as well as its variations and extremes over many years, is called climate. For example, the city of Las Vegas in the U.S. state of Nevada is generally dry and hot. Honolulu, the capital of the U.S. state of Hawaii, is also hot, but much more humid and rainy.

\n\nClimate changes, just like weather. However, climate change can take hundreds or even thousands of years. Today, the Sahara Desert in northern Africa is the largest desert in the world. However, several thousand years ago, the climate in the Sahara was quite different. This “Green Sahara” experienced frequent rainy weather.

\n\nEnd of Reading !!! ✔
    </string>
    <string name="information_Q_2">
Ans. Climate change is any systematic change in the long-term statistics of climate variables such as temperature, precipitation, pressure, or wind sustained over several decades or longer. Climate change can be due to natural external forcings (changes in solar emission or changes in the earth’s orbit, natural internal processes of the climate system) or it can be human induced.
\n\nThe classical period used for describing a climate is 30 years, as defined by the World Meteorological Organization (WMO).

\n\nEnd of Reading !!! ✔
    </string>
    <string name="information_Q_3">
Ans. Scientists attribute the global warming trend observed since the mid-20th century to the human expansion of the "greenhouse effect" — warming that results when the atmosphere traps heat radiating from Earth toward space.
Certain gases in the atmosphere block heat from escaping. Long-lived gases that remain semi-permanently in the atmosphere and do not respond physically or chemically to changes in temperature are described as "forcing" climate change. Gases, such as water vapor, which respond physically or chemically to changes in temperature are seen as "feedback."
\n\n◉ Water vapor. The most abundant greenhouse gas, but importantly, it acts as a feedback to the climate. Water vapor increases as the Earths atmosphere warms, but so does the possibility of clouds and precipitation, making these some of the most important feedback mechanisms to the greenhouse effect.
\n\n◉ Carbon dioxide (CO2). A minor but very important component of the atmosphere, carbon dioxide is released through natural processes such as respiration and volcano eruptions and through human activities such as deforestation, land use changes, and burning fossil fuels. Humans have increased atmospheric CO2 concentration by 47% since the Industrial Revolution began. This is the most important long-lived "forcing" of climate change.
\n\n◉ Methane. A hydrocarbon gas produced both through natural sources and human activities, including the decomposition of wastes in landfills, agriculture, and especially rice cultivation, as well as ruminant digestion and manure management associated with domestic livestock. On a molecule-for-molecule basis, methane is a far more active greenhouse gas than carbon dioxide, but also one which is much less abundant in the atmosphere.
\n\n◉ Nitrous oxide. A powerful greenhouse gas produced by soil cultivation practices, especially the use of commercial and organic fertilizers, fossil fuel combustion, nitric acid production, and biomass burning.
\n\n◉ Chlorofluorocarbons (CFCs). Synthetic compounds entirely of industrial origin used in a number of applications, but now largely regulated in production and release to the atmosphere by international agreement for their ability to contribute to destruction of the ozone layer. They are also greenhouse gases.
\n\n◉ Not enough greenhouse effect: The planet Mars has a very thin atmosphere, nearly all carbon dioxide. Because of the low atmospheric pressure, and with little to no methane or water vapor to reinforce the weak greenhouse effect, Mars has a largely frozen surface that shows no evidence of life.
\n\n◉ Too much greenhouse effect: The atmosphere of Venus, like Mars, is nearly all carbon dioxide. But Venus has about 154,000 times as much carbon dioxide in its atmosphere as Earth (and about 19,000 times as much as Mars does), producing a runaway greenhouse effect and a surface temperature hot enough to melt lead.
\n\n On Earth, human activities are changing the natural greenhouse. Over the last century the burning of fossil fuels like coal and oil has increased the concentration of atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO2). This happens because the coal or oil burning process combines carbon with oxygen in the air to make CO2. To a lesser extent, the clearing of land for agriculture, industry, and other human activities has increased concentrations of greenhouse gases.
\n\n The consequences of changing the natural atmospheric greenhouse are difficult to predict, but some effects seem likely:
\n\n◉ On average, Earth will become warmer. Some regions may welcome warmer temperatures, but others may not.
\n\n◉ Warmer conditions will probably lead to more evaporation and precipitation overall, but individual regions will vary, some becoming wetter and others dryer.
\n\n◉ A stronger greenhouse effect will warm the ocean and partially melt glaciers and ice sheets, increasing sea level. Ocean water also will expand if it warms, contributing further to sea level rise.
\n\n◉ Outside of a greenhouse, higher atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO2) levels can have both positive and negative effects on crop Fields. Some laboratory experiments suggest that elevated CO2 levels can increase plant growth. However, other factors, such as changing temperatures, ozone, and water and nutrient constraints, may more than counteract any potential increase in field. If optimal temperature ranges for some crops are exceeded, earlier possible gains in yield may be reduced or reversed altogether.
\n\n➥ Climate extremes, such as droughts, floods and extreme temperatures, can lead to crop losses and threaten the livelihoods of agricultural producers and the food security of communities worldwide. Depending on the crop and ecosystem, weeds, pests, and fungi can also thrive under warmer temperatures, wetter climates, and increased CO2 levels, and climate change will likely increase weeds and pests.
\n\n➥ Finally, although rising CO2 can stimulate plant growth, research has shown that it can also reduce the nutritional value of most food crops by reducing the concentrations of protein and essential minerals in most plant species. Climate change can cause new patterns of pests and diseases to emerge, affecting plants, animals and humans, and posing new risks for food security, food safety and human health.

\n\nEnd of Reading !!! ✔
    </string>
    <string name="information_Q_4">
Ans. Global climate change has already had observable effects on the environment. Glaciers have shrunk, ice on rivers and lakes is breaking up earlier, plant and animal ranges have shifted and trees are flowering sooner.
\n\nEffects that scientists had predicted in the past would result from global climate change are now occurring: loss of sea ice, accelerated sea level rise and longer, more intense heat waves.

\n\nTaken as a whole, the range of published evidence indicates that the net damage costs of climate change are likely to be significant and to increase over time.
\n\n- Speech Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change

\n\n✔ Scientists have high confidence that global temperatures will continue to rise for decades to come, largely due to greenhouse gases produced by human activities. The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC), which includes more than 1,300 scientists from the United States and other countries, forecasts a temperature rise of 2.5 to 10 degrees Fahrenheit over the next century.
\n\n✔ According to the IPCC, the extent of climate change effects on individual regions will vary over time and with the ability of different societal and environmental systems to mitigate or adapt to change.
\n\n✔ The IPCC predicts that increases in global mean temperature of less than 1.8 to 5.4 degrees Fahrenheit (1 to 3 degrees Celsius) above 1990 levels will produce beneficial impacts in some regions and harmful ones in others. Net annual costs will increase over time as global temperatures increase.
\n\n✔ "Taken as a whole," the IPCC states, "the range of published evidence indicates that the net damage costs of climate change are likely to be significant and to increase over time."


\n\nEnd of Reading !!! ✔
    </string>
    <string name="information_Q_5">
Ans. The planets average surface temperature has risen about 2.12 degrees Fahrenheit (1.18 degrees Celsius) since the late 19th century, a change driven largely by increased carbon dioxide emissions into the atmosphere and other human activities. Most of the warming occurred in the past 40 years, with the seven most recent years being the warmest.
\n\nThe years 2016 and 2020 are tied for the warmest year on record.

\n\nEnd of Reading !!! ✔
    </string>
    <string name="information_Q_7">
Ans. The Gangotri glacier holds a place of great significance for Indians. Located in the Uttarkashi District of Uttarakhand, this glacier is not only among the largest in the Himalayas, but also one of the primary sources of water for river Ganga. Moreover, it is a pilgrimage site for devout Hindus, while also being popular within the trekking circles.
\n\nThe glacier has faced constant threat of excessive melting, as global warming continues unabated. Now, the Ministry of Science and Technology has said that factors like agricultural burning and forest fires could trigger large-scale glacial melting in Gangotri come summer.
\n\nThe melting of Gangotri could lead to enormous short- as well as long-term consequences for the entire country. The immediate effect of the melting is likely to be in the form of floods, as glacial melt will lead to the accumulation of excess water in glacial lakes. Flooding of such lakes, along with rivers and other reservoirs, could wreak havoc in multiple north Indian states. Such intense inundation will not only damage the environment, but also force the regional residents to migrate southward.
\n\nOnce the flooding phases out, droughts will set in due to the disappearance of the water source, which could further pose severe challenges to water and food security in the region. Ganga’s stream would possibly narrow down, and the river may very well become a seasonal one. Its basins could also undergo desertification due to the lack of water year-round, causing great harm to flora, fauna and human settlements that dwell around the river. Multiple societal and cultural changes across India could follow.

\n\nEnd of Reading !!! ✔
    </string>
    <string name="information_Q_8">
Ans. Hurricane Katrina was the costliest storm in U.S. history, and its effects are still felt today in New Orleans and coastal Louisiana.
\n\nHurricane Katrina made landfall off the coast of Louisiana on August 29, 2005. It hit land as a Category 3 storm with winds reaching speeds as high as 120 miles per hour. Because of the ensuing destruction and loss of life, the storm is often considered one of the worst in U.S. history. An estimated 1,200 people died as a direct result of the storm, which also cost an estimated $108 billion in property damage, making it the costliest storm on record.
\n\nThe devastating aftermath of Hurricane Katrina exposed a series of deep-rooted problems, including controversies over the federal governments response, difficulties in search-and-rescue efforts, and lack of preparedness for the storm, particularly with regard to the city aging series of levees—50 of which failed during the storm, significantly flooding the low-lying city and causing much of the damage. Katrinas victims tended to be low income and African American in disproportionate numbers, and many of those who lost their homes faced years of hardship.
\n\nTen years after the disaster, then-President Barack Obama said of Katrina, "What started out as a natural disaster became a man-made disaster—a failure of government to look out for its own citizens."
\n\nThe city of New Orleans and other coastal communities in Katrinas path remain significantly altered more than a decade after the storm, both physically and culturally. The damage was so extensive that some pundits had argued, controversially, that New Orleans should be permanently abandoned, even as the city vowed to rebuild.
\n\nThe population of New Orleans fell by more than half in the year after Katrina, according to Data Center Research. As of this writing, the population had grown back to nearly 80 percent of where it was before the hurricane.

\n\nEnd of Reading !!! ✔
    </string>
    <string name="information_Q_9">
Ans. "Its been like this every day and its always about the same thing. The fire."
\nThe phone rings incessantly at Sílvia Bentos desk in the Pedrógão Grande Mayors office.
\n\nIt was on 17 June last year that a wildfire raged through this part of central Portugal, devastating an area four times the size of Lisbon, destroying hundreds of homes and killing 66 people.
\n\nMany victims were trapped in their homes or in their cars as they tried to escape. It was the deadliest fire in Portuguese history.
\n\n"Its like it was yesterday," says Sílvia Bento.
\n\nA year on, the ferocity and the scope of this tragedy are marked by thousands of acres of black and brown mountains and valleys stretching as far as the horizon.

\n\nThe constant buzz of chainsaws suggests work on reviving the area has begun. But a lack of funding, a lack of people and the sheer shock of the disaster mean it will take some time for this part of central Portugal to recover.
\n\nToll of the Pedrógão Grande fire
\n\n●	66 people killed, many of them trapped in vehicles on the N-236 road
\n\n●	253 injured
\n\n●	485 houses destroyed
\n\n●	53,000 hectares of land burned, including 20,000 hectares of forest
\n\n●	2,018 farmers affected at a cost of €21m (£19m; $25m)
\n\n●	49 companies affected at a cost of €31m
\n\n"Even after what happened, the locals look around and everything reminds them of what happened. Even if they want to avoid that reality, they cant," says Ana Santos, an expert in grief therapy at the PIN psychology centre.
\n\nShe says there are several cases of mourning and severe trauma in the area surrounding the councils of Pedrógão Grande, Castanheira de Pêra and Figueiró dos Vinhos.
Ana Margarida Teixeira, a local psychologist working on the ground since day one, says cases of post-traumatic stress disorder are rare but that almost every week new patients sign in at the public health clinic where she works.
\n\n"The population has been very resilient. They are looking at what happened as an opportunity for growth and there is less stigma regarding asking for help than I thought," she says.

\n\nAmong the survivors who has sought help is Lídia Antunes, whose family survived the disaster, but only just.
\n\nOn the day of the fire, they fled their house in three different cars. They soon lost track of each other and became cut off on flame-ridden forest roads.
\n\n"I was convinced I was going to die. I was speeding through flames and it was so hot, I though if I tried to U-turn the car would melt," she says. "At some point I got lost and got hit by another car but I just kept speeding. I knew that as soon as the car stopped I would die."
She drove on and ended up saving a couple pleading for help.

\n\n"Life is getting back to normal," says Silvia Bento at the mayors office. "People dont talk about it every day any more.
\n\n"But its in our minds every day. Definitely, we will never forget".

\n\nEnd of Reading !!! ✔
    </string>
    <string name="information_Q_10">
Ans. Climate change is one of the most challenging problems that humanity has ever faced. At stake are hundreds of millions of lives, innumerable species and ecosystems, the health and viability of the economy, and the future habitability of this planet.
Fortunately, climate change is solvable. We have the technologies. We have the science. We now need the leadership—and the courage to change course.
\n\n# Cut Emissions
\nCarbon dioxide and other heat-trapping gases are the main drivers of global warming. While climate change cannot be stopped, it can be slowed.
\n\nTo avoid the worst consequences of climate change, we’ll need to reach “net zero” carbon emissions by 2050 or sooner. Net zero means that, on balance, no more carbon is dumped into the atmosphere than is taken out.
\n\nTo achieve net zero emissions, we need a massive transformation in how we produce and consume electricity. We need a newer, better transportation system. We need to stop deforestation. We need a climate-friendly agricultural system.
\n\nThe scale of these changes will require significant federal policy that puts a price on carbon. It also requires international cooperation: the Paris Agreement, signed in 2016, reflects the world’s best effort to solve climate change so far, though it doesn’t include the emissions reductions we need.
\n\nMuch remains to be done—and we need to do it as quickly as possible.
\n\n# Remove Carbon Dioxide
\nTo reach net zero emissions, we need to do more than just reduce our emissions: we need to actively remove carbon dioxide from the atmosphere or offset its effects.
\n\nThe easiest way to do this is by planting new forests (afforestation) or restoring old ones (reforestation). Other enhanced land management practices can help, as can new technologies that suck CO2 out of the air (“direct air capture”), or prevent it from leaving smokestacks (“carbon capture and storage”).
\n\nScale, speed, and cost are the main barriers to all these technologies and approaches. In the United States, strong state- and federal-level policies—and large-scale investment in research and development—are crucial.
\n\n# Flight Disinformation
\nFor years, media pundits, partisan think tanks, and special interest groups funded by fossil fuel companies have raised doubts about the truth of global warming.
\n\nThese contrarians downplay and distort the evidence of climate change, lobby for policies that reward polluters, and attempt to undercut existing pollution standards.
\n\nThis barrage of disinformation misleads and confuses the public about the growing consequences of global warming and makes it more difficult to implement the solutions we really need. Until the influence of these special interests is sufficiently diminished, climate action will be that much harder.
\n\n# Prepare and Adapt
\nNo matter how quickly we reduce emissions, the reality is that certain climate impacts are inevitable. The seas are rising. Temperatures break records every year.
\n\nDroughts, floods, and extreme weather are damaging communities today.
\n\nCutting carbon is the only long-term solution for avoiding climate impacts. In the short-term, we need to adapt. That means everything from discouraging development in high-risk areas, to planning for water scarcity, to building more resilient cities and communities. Investments should be scientifically sound and socially just, and focused where the impacts are greatest—often in low-income communities and communities of color.

\n\nEnd of Reading !!! ✔
    </string>
    <string name="give_credit">
1.	Wikipedia
\n\n2.	National Aeronautics and Space Administration
\n\n3.	Met Office - Weather
\n\n4.	Our Changing Climate
\n\n5.	National Geographic
\n\n6.	Weather.com
\n\n7.	BBC News
\n\n8.	NBC News
        \n\n\nThanks to Everyone !!!
    </string>
    <string name="about_this_app">
This app is made by Pratik Chakraborty. This app will let you Know Everything About Climate. \n\nSo, that this app is named as Know About Climate (KAC). I mean, form this app you will know "What is Weather", "What is Climate" and many more thing. \n\nJust click on "Climate Questions" and Learn about Climate !
        \n\n\nThank You for Reading !!!
    </string>

</resources>